If there's one single highest leverage
skill you can learn to radically
transform the quality of your life for
better, it's content creation.
I want to show you a clip from 2017,
and this was the first time I'd ever
spoken to camera.
Oh, how we doing?
Do I look big?
I feel like I'm being
interviewed. You got the job already,
James.
You signed on the line.
There's no need to be nervous.
My name's James Smith.
I'm a personal trainer from England,
from the UK, near Windsor.
Recently moved to Australia to come to the
center of the fitness industry
to take over. You could tell
that my mannerisms,
my ability to talk to camera,
they've improved quite a lot since,
and so has the quality of my life.
Now,
I think you maybe don't have the right
relationship with social media.
You might think that we
are just posting videos for people to
watch, and that
couldn't be further from the truth.
This morning,
I got a refund request from someone,
said that what I was teaching
was too surface level. And I thought,
"Wow,
I've got someone really advanced here.
Let me have a look at your Instagram."
Zero posts.
Now, chances are if you're watching this,
the hardest hurdle is to go from zero to
one. And ultimately,
I think the reason you haven't started
posting content yet is
because you maybe don't fully understand
what you're about to get into.
And if you did, you'd be posting.
First of all,
let's remove it from context.
Let's imagine you
are creating a play in the theater.
And by the way, I hate that shit.
I'd rather wank off my grandad than go to
the
theater. Just throwing it out there.
When people are like, "Oh, it
was fantastic." Shut up.
Anyway, for theater,
you have to put together a play,
you have to cast, you have to
rehearse, you have to get it perfect.
And on the night, you've got a crowd,
they've paid money to be in there, and
if you
don't get it right, you're a failure.
They're going to write an article in the
local newspaper, and your name will be
tarnished forever.
But in the world of social media,
you can create a piece of
content that's average or not that good,
and it just won't really get seen that
much. That's how the algorithm works.
It'll be given to a small amount of
people, and based on how they react,
it will go
further and further wide. Quite literally,
every single social media platform wants
your next video to get a billion views.
But it's just not good enough yet,
and nor should it be.
You've just got into this.
Similar to when I started in
that clip before.
How can you be good at something
that you've not done much?
It's retarded